[
    {
        "question": "1. Members of a society are expected to adhere to societal values for the following reasons except?", 
        "optionA": "enhancement of development", 
        "optionB": "Improvement of self dignity", 
        "optionC": "reduction of social vices",
        "optionD": "relegation of morality",
        "answer": "relegation of morality"
    },
    {
        "question": "2. The defence of the territorial integrity of a country by her people is part of?", 
        "optionA": "political participation", 
        "optionB": "political culture", 
        "optionC": "self determination",
        "optionD": "duties and obligation",
        "answer": "duties and obligation" 
    },
    {
        "question": "3. A program established to foster common ties among Nigerians is",
        "optionA": "Subsidy Re-investment Program (SURE-P)",
        "optionB": "National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)",
        "optionC": "Universal Basic Education (UBE)",
        "optionD": "Education Trust Fund (ETF)",
        "answer": "National Youth Service Corps (NYSC)"
    },
    {
        "question": "4. A common repercussion for drug abuse is?",
        "optionA": "medication",
        "optionB": "rehabilitation",
        "optionC": "brain drain",
        "optionD": "memory loss",
        "answer": "brain drain"
    },
    {
        "question": "5. Which of the following is a way of preventing drug traficking?",
        "optionA": "foreign scholarship",
        "optionB": "employment",
        "optionC": "motivation",
        "optionD": "indulging offenders",
        "answer": "employment"
    },
    {
        "question": "6. Which of the following is not a  form of stigmatization",
        "optionA": "refusal to interact with family of an HIV patient",
        "optionB": "physical and verbal abuse of an HIV patient",
        "optionC": "enlightening people living with HIV/AIDS",
        "optionD": "ostracizing HIV patients",
        "answer": "enlightening people living with HIV/AIDS"
    },
    {
        "question": "7. In a democratic government, franchise is given to all",
        "optionA": "party members",
        "optionB": "adult citizens",
        "optionC": "resident adults",
        "optionD": "opinion leaders",
        "answer": "adult citizens"
    },
    {
        "question": "8. A significant companion of the rule of law is the",
        "optionA": "fusion of legislative and executive functions",
        "optionB": "adoption of one party system",
        "optionC": "enforcement of law by the legislature",
        "optionD": "supremacy of the ordinary law",
        "answer": "supremacy of the ordinary law"
    },
    {
        "question": "9. Operation of the rule of law could be undermined by?",
        "optionA": "existence of civil society groups",
        "optionB": "existence of free press",
        "optionC": "establishment of administrative tribunal",
        "optionD": "encouragement of effective opposition",
        "answer": "establishment of administrative tribunal"
    },
    {
        "question": "10. The smooth operation of the public service in Nigeria is being hampered by",
        "optionA": "debt burden",
        "optionB": "adequate training",
        "optionC": "privatization",
        "optionD": "bribery and corruption",
        "answer": "bribery and corruption"
    }
]